Rachel Suzanne Torres

rachel-torres@uiowa.edu | @torrespolisci | UIowa

Pronouns: She/Her/Hers

Bio

Hola! My name is **Rachel Torres** and I'm currently a graduate student at the **University of Iowa** working on my doctoral degree. I graduated from the University of North Texas with a B.A. in Political Science in 2016, and was previously a McNair Scholar. Im 2015, I participated in UNT's National Science Foundation sponsored Research Experience for Undergraduates on 'Conflict and Peace Studies'.

My dissertation is related to the political beliefs and behaviors of both foreign- and nativeborn Latinos, as well as the impact of variation in policy implementation within an individual's local context.

Research Interests

Immigration, Immigration Enforcement, Latina/o/x Politics, Push/Pull Migration Factors, Policy Feedback Effects, Policy Environments, Contextual Factors.

Education

2016-current Ph.D. in Political Science, University of Iowa

Advisor: Dr. Rene Rocha

2018 M.A. in Political Science, University of Iowa

Advisor: Dr. Rene Rocha

2016 B.A. in Political Science, University of North Texas

Minor: French

Advisor: Dr. Regina Branton

Academic Appointments

2019–2020 Latinidades Dissertation Fellowship for Mellon-Sawyer Seminar's "Imagining Latinidades: Articulations of National Belonging" housed in the Obermann Center for Advanced Studies and funded by the Mellon Foundation, **University of Iowa**.

2016-2018 Research Assistant to Dr. Fredrick Solt, University of Iowa.

2015 Research Assistant to Dr. Regina Branton, University of North Texas.

Teaching Experience

2019 Online Course Instructor, **University of Iowa** Introduction to the Politics of Race , 1 semester; Developed original syllabus, created course materials, graded assignments

2019 Course Instructor, University of Iowa. Immigration Politics, 1 semester; Developed original syllabus, created course materials, held weekly discussion sections, graded papers

2018 Teaching Assistant, University of Iowa. Intro to American Politics, 1 semester, 1 section; Conducted weekly discussion sections, graded papers

2016 Teaching Assistant, University of Iowa. Intro to Political Communication, 1 semester, 3 sections; Conducted weekly discussion sections, graded papers

Honors and Awards

- 2019 Recipient of the American Political Science Association's Latino Caucus Travel Fund
- 2018 Recipient of the American Political Science Association's Fund for Latino Scholarship
- 2018 Underrepresented Minority Pre-Comprehensive Mentored Summer Research Fellowship awardee
- 2017 American Political Science Association's Minority Fellowship Program Recipient
- 2017 Underrepresented Minority Pre-Comprehensive Mentored Summer Research Fellowship awardee
- 2016 University of North Texas's Outstanding Undergraduate Political Science Student
- 2015 Recipient of NSF REU grant in Civil Conflict Management and Peace Studies
- 2013 Recipient of Frank B. Feigert Award at University of North Texas's Scholars Day

Papers and Presentations

2019 "Spinning the Money Web: Private Prison Companies, Lobbyists, and the Cosponsorship of Punitive Immigration Legislation in the U.S. House of Representatives" (coauthored with Jason L. Morin and Loren Collingwood) jointly presented at the Western Political Science Association.

2018–2019 "Policing Participation: Policy Feedback in Context" (coauthored with Elizabeth Maltby and Jielu Yao) jointly presented at the American Political Science Association and the Western Political Science Association.

2018–2019 "When Policy Clashes: Understanding Policy Feedback of Social Program in Varying Policy Environmentsm" (coauthored with Rene Rocha, Jielu Yao, and Adriano Udani) presented at the Midwest Political Science Association, the Western Political Science Association, and the UCDavis PRIEC meeting.

2016 "¡Qué lejos estoy del suelo donde he nacido!: Location, Immigration and Acculturation," (coauthored with Regina Branton), jointly presented at Midwest Political Science Association.

2016 "Through His Eyes: Critical Analysis of Wright's Native Son and Dostoyevsky's Crime and Punishment" in 'Social Circumstance and Aesthetic Achievement: Contextual Studies in Richard Wright's Native Son', University of North Texas Libraries.

Professional Development

Positions Held

2019–2021 Elected to the Excecutive Council of the American Political Science Association's Migration and Citizenship Section.

2018–2019 Appointed as Social Media Chair of American Political Science Association's Migration and Citizenship Section.

2017-current Elected to serve as a UIowa's Graduate Association of Political Science (GAPS) Officer

Cerifications

2016 Latina/o and Mexican American Studies (LMAS) Certificate from the University of North Texas2015 French Technical Certificate from College International de Cannes(Last updated: May 29, 2019)